# Ntuthuko Trevor Dlamini

Mid-Level Software Engineer

Parklands, Cape Town Phone: +27 81 770 2214

Email: <a href="mailto:ntu2kotrevor@gmail.com">ntu2kotrevor@gmail.com</a>

GitHub Profile: https://github.com/Ntu2koTrevor

Software Engineer with extensive experience in mobile web applications, USSD applications, working with API's using Django Rest Framework and passionate about finding solutions to everyday problems using technology, especially when it is applied to improve the lives of less privileged people.

## **Key Skills and Competencies**

Python, Javascript, PHP, Java, HTML, CSS, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite3, Pandas, GitHub, Travis, Unittest, Mocha, QUnit, Pytest, Trial, Graphql, Scrum, Kanban boards on Jira, Trello, Retrospectives, Daily Stand Ups, Backlog, grooming, Sphinx, Node.Js, Gulp, Bootstrap, Arduino, Vumi, Molo Mentoring and Wagtail

### Work Experience

#### Picsa, Cape Town - Software Engineer

September 2017 - April 2018

- Developed and maintained clean and simple code written in Python.
- Created spreadsheets and reports using pandas
- Produced tests for all production-ready code.

#### FinChatBot, Cape Town - Software Engineer

June 2017 - August 2017

- Built Chatbots with Node.JS
- Worked with Swagger for developing API's
- Reviewed other developers code
- Helped estimate tasks
- Took lead on Scrum meetings (Sprint planning, Retrospective and Daily standups)

#### Praekelt.Org, Cape Town - Software Engineer

May 2015 - May 2017

- Worked on a range of different projects and platforms, from Vumi application and API's to project-specific API's.
- Contributed to "Ways Of Working" documentation that covered Django topics like Nginx, Gunicorn, Postgresql and Migration.
- Wrote a tutorial on how to write a Javascript Sandbox Application (<a href="http://vumi-jssandbox-toolkit.readthedocs.io/en/master/tutorial/index.html">http://vumi-jssandbox-toolkit.readthedocs.io/en/master/tutorial/index.html</a>).
- Worked on Molo Core and Molo applications using Python and Django framework.
- Read about an open source project and gave an overview of it to the engineering team.
- Debugged existing source code and polish feature sets.
- Helped estimate Jira tickets
- Reviewed other developers code

# **Education and Training**

#### Project codeX, Cape Town

February 2015 - May 2015

During my studies at project codeX, I had the opportunity to hone my skills in Node, Git, Github, Travis, Mocha, QUnit, Gulp and Agile Methodology.

Project: Created an educational quiz app which provides a fun experience, using an open data set. I used HTML, CSS, Javascript and NASA API.

PC Training & Business College, Durban - Diploma in Information Technology

February 2012 - December 2013

PC Training & Business College, Durban - Higher Certificate in Systems Engineering

February 2011 - December 2011

## **High School Qualification**

Merebank Secondary School, Durban - Matric

2005 - 2009

### **Awards**

- International Space Apps Challenge: Galactics Problem Solver
- Outstanding Academic Achievement Award in Microprocessor

### References

Available on request